Today we have gathered here to do the Navaratri Puja.
امروز اینجا گرد هم آمده‌ایم تا پوجای نورتری را انجام دهیم.
There were nine times when the major incarnations
برای نُه مرتبه،
of the Mother of this universe
اینکارنیشن‌های اصلی مادر این عالم،
were manifested. They were manifested with a purpose.
ظهور پیدا کردند. آنها با یک هدف ظهور یافتند.
That purpose is to protect Her bhaktas, Her disciples, Her children.
هدف آن است که بْهاکتاها، شاگردان و فرزندانش را حفاظت کند.
This was
این عشقی الزام‌آور بود.
Mother's love is binding, She cannot escape it
عشق مادر الزام‌آور است. نمی‌تواند از آن فرار کند.
and She has to manifest it, work it out
و می‌بایست که آن را نشان دهد، به کار گیرد
and give that protection to all Her children.
و به فرزندانش حمایت برساند.
This protection in the modern times has taken another form.
این حمایت در دوران مدرن شکلی دیگر یافته است.
In those days, the evil was trying
در آن دوران شیطان سعی داشت
to harm, to destroy the people who were righteous,
به انسان‌های درستکار، سرسپرده و نیکوکار
who were bhaktas, who were doing good things,
که خواهان ادامه یک زندگی بسیار مذهبی بودند
who wanted to lead a very religious life.
صدمه بزند و نابود کند.
So to save them, She incarnated. To protect them, She incarnated.
به همین دلیل برای نجات آنها، مادر عالم بر زمین آمد. برای حفاظت از آنها بر زمین آمد.
But they knew what was good, they knew what was wrong.
ولی آنها می دانستند خوب چیست. می‌دانستند بد کدام است
And they wanted to preserve their good life, their precious life.
و می‌خواستند زندگی خوب خود، زندگی ارزشمند خود را حفظ کنند.
They didn't care for money, they didn't care for power,
آنها به پول اهمیتی نمی‌دادند، آنها به قدرت اهمیتی نمی‌دادند،
but just they wanted their life,
بلکه فقط زندگی خود را می‌خواستند،
means they wanted to be alive to worship the Goddess.
یعنی می‌خواستند زنده بمانند؛ برای این که ایزدبانو را ستایش کنند
And when they were troubled or harmed or destroyed
و وقتی آنها به دست این نیروهای اهریمنی،
by these evil forces, She had to manifest.
دچار مشکل یا صدمه می‌شدند یا از بین می‌رفتند، او به ناچار ظهور می‌کرد.
But in modern times it's become very complicated
ولی در دوران جدید این مسئله پیچیده شده است؛
as the modern times are complicated.
چرا که دوران جدید هم پیچیده است.
First of all,
اول این که
in the mind, in the lifestyle, in the society
در ذهن، در شیوه زندگی، درجامعه انسان‌های خوب
of good human beings, righteous human beings,
و انسان‌های درستکار،
fear of the wrong has entered.
ترس از اشتباه وارد شده است.
Like they are afraid say of their priests, of their churches,
مثلا آنها از کشیش‌‌هایشان، از کلیساهایشان،
of their temples, of their mosques, which are all false.
از معابدشان و از مساجدشان که همه دروغین هستند، می‌ترسند.
They are not afraid of God, they don't believe in God.
آنها از خدا نمی‌ترسند. آنها به خدا اعتقادی ندارند.
They think they have created God and they can manage God. So who is God?
فکر می‌کنند آنها خدا را خلق کرده‌اند و می‌توانند او را اداره کنند. پس خدا دیگر کیست؟
The way they behave you can see clearly that they do not recognize
از رفتارشان می‌شود به وضوح دید که نمی‌توانند
the existence of God, God Almighty who is a wrathful God.
وجود خدا را  تشخیص دهند، خداوند متعالی که خدایی خشمگین است.
They are not at all worried as to what will happen to them.
آنها اصلا از آنچه که بر سرشان خواهد آمد، بیمی به دل راه نمی‌دهند.
They don't even believe in the second life, they don't believe in the resurrection.
حتی به زندگی دوباره اعتقاد ندارند، آنها به رستاخیز اعتقاد ندارند.
They are very short-sighted, evil people doing all kinds of evil things.
آنها خیلی کوته‌بین هستند. افراد شیطانی دست به هر کار شیطانی می‌زنند.
So somehow or other, as soon as you are born,
بنابراین، به محض این که به دنیا می‌آیید،
you are born into some sort of a brand,
بالاخره با یک برچسبی به دنیا می‌آیید،
you are this, you are that, you are that, you are that, as soon as you are born.
شما این هستید. شما آن هستید. شما آن هستید. شما آن هستید. به محض این که به دنیا بیایید.
So the first brand comes onto this modern man,
پس اولین برچسبی که به انسان عصر جدید می‌چسبانند،
is of what religion to which he belongs.
مذهبی است که به آن تعلق دارد.
He can't avoid it, he has to be jolly well belonging to some religion.
راه فراری نیست. باید دلش هم بخواهد که مال یک مذهبی باشد.
You go anywhere, even in the passport - nowadays they have stopped it -
هر جا بروید، حتی در پاسپورت؛ البته دیگر این کار را نمی‌کنند؛
otherwise they used to ask: "What is your religion?"
وگرنه می‌پرسیدند: مذهبت چیست؟
And in India if you said you had no religion they would not give you a passport
و اگر در هند می‌گفتی که مذهبی نداری، به تو پاسپورت نمی‌دادند؛
because you are not yet qualified evil person,
چون هنوز آدم فاسد واجد شرایطی نیستی،
or you are not following qualified evil people.
یا از افراد فاسد واجد شرایط پیروی نمی‌کنی.
So that very simple gullible good people, very righteous believers of God,
برای همین آدم‌های بسیار ساده و زودباور، آدم‌های خوب، بسیار درستکار و معتقدان به خدا،
developed this kind of a fear which was put into their heads by these false people.
ترسی پیدا کردند که به دست این آدم‌های دغلکار به دلشان افتاد،
That if you don't do like this, if you don't pay money to us,
که اگر این کار را نکنی، اگر به ما پول ندهی، آن وقت خدا از تو خشمگین می‌شود،
If you do not come to the confession, then God will be angry with you,
اگر نیایی اعتراف کنی،
if you do not tolerate our nonsense, God will be angry with you.
اگر تحمل مزخرفات ما را نداشته باشی، خدا از دستت عصبانی می‌شود.
All these things started going into the brains of the people very easily.
تمام این مطالب به راحتی وارد مغز مردم شد.
In some religion they believe there is no sin in drinking.
در برخی مذاهب، اعتقاد دارند نوشیدن مشروب گناهی ندارد.
no sin in marrying many women.
در برخی مذاهب می‌گویند اگر با زنان زیادی ازدواج کنی گناهی ندارد.
In some religion they believe that you can have caste system.
در برخی مذاهب می‌گویند می‌شود سیستم طبقاتی داشت.
All is anti-God, absolutely anti-God activity perpetuated into the society
همه ضدخدا هستند. اعمال مطلقا ضدخدایی را این کشیش‌ها که قرار است
by these priests who are supposed to be in charge of the religion.
مسئول مذهب باشند، در جامعه جا انداخته‌اند.
So the first horrible conditioning we have when we start Sahaja Yoga is this.
پس اولین قید و شرط بسیار بدی که موقع شروع ساهاجایوگا داریم این است.
So to start something afresh they find it very difficult.
برای همین به نظرشان سخت می‌آید که کاری جدید را شروع کنند.
So the first protection Mother had to render is from this conditioning.
پس اولین حفاظتی که مادر باید تأمین کند، در مقابل این قید و شرط است.
The second one is that of the country.
دومین قید و شرط مال کشور است.
Either you belong to this country, to that country, or to that country.
شما یا به این کشور تعلق دارید، یا به آن کشور یا به آن کشور؛
And these days every country is competing with each other in all kinds of
و امروزه تمام کشورها در انواع
corruption, mafia, all kinds of things, every country.
فساد، مافیا و غیره رقابت دارند؛ تمام کشورها.
Suddenly you discover.
یک مرتبه می‌فهمید؛
You have faith in one country, you find, oh no, no, they were supporting
به یک کشور ایمان دارید، می‌بینید وای نه، نه! اینها دارند
certain person secretly.
مخفیانه از یک نفر حمایت می‌کنند.
So whether they are democratic or anything,
پس چه دموکرات باشند یا هر چیز،
there is a kind of a mafia working everywhere under some name.
همه جا نوعی مافیا در لوای یک اسم دارد کار می‌کند.
So the so-called laws also are only for people who are simple, gullible,
پس این به اصطلاح قوانین، فقط برای کسانی است که شهروندانی ساده، زودباور
pure citizens, and not for the people who put those laws on them.
و پاک هستند؛ نه برای آنها که خود، این قوانین را برایشان گذاشته‌اند.
They take bribes, they take all kinds of things, but still
آنها رشوه می‌گیرند. همه کاری انجام می‌دهند. ولی با این حال
they are supposed to be in charge of law, doing all kinds of illegal things,
قرار است مسئول قانون باشند. هر کار غیرقانونی از آنها سرمی‌زند؛
because they have made the law, so they know how to be illegal.
چون خودشان قانون را درست کرده‌اند، می‌دانند چطور خلاف کنند.
So this is the second type of fear that is in the minds of the modern time.
این نوع دوم ترس هست که در مغزهای مدل جدید وجود دارد.
Then the third thing was the war. Wars after wars came in,
سومین آنها جنگ بود. جنگ‌ها یکی بعد از دیگری پیش آمدند.
so many people developed a kind of a fear about war,
برای همین بسیاری از مردم نوعی ترس از جنگ پیدا کردند
and as a reaction they developed a kind of a stupid ego,
و برای همین در واکنش به آن، یک جور ایگوی احمقانه پیدا کردند،
just they said, to protect themselves.
فقط حرفشان این بود که برای حفاظت از خودشان است.
In protection, themselves, they have built up a big ego
برای محفاظت از خودشان آنها ایگوی بزرگی ساختند
and they are now becoming very, we should say, aggressive people.
که باعث شد الان آنها آدم‌های بسیار مهاجمی شوند.
So this kind of a wider range, I should say, of fear,
پس این طیف وسیع ازترس
it can be directed into any direction, it can be directed towards anyone.
می‌‌تواند به هر سمتی سوق پیدا کند. به هر شخصی می‌تواند سوق یابد.
Then comes - is the fear of race - racialism.
بعد نوبت ترس از نژاد است؛ نژادپرستی.
Now I'm told that neo-nazism is taking its own course
حالا به من گفته شده که نئونازیسم دارد کار خودش را می‌کند
and is coming up like a little snake.
و مثل یک مار کوچک خود را دارد نشان می‌دهد.
So this is another area which is very dangerous now, working out.
این هم حیطه دیگری است که امروزه به شکل خیلی خطرناکی دارد عمل می‌کند.
Now in the minds of seekers - in their seeking,
حالا در ذهن جستجوگران و در جستجوگری‌شان
they have been to many gurus, they have read all kinds of books
استادهای زیادی داشته‌اند، هر نوع کتابی را خوانده‌اند،
but they were seeking, you know. They can, they were seeking, yet...
ولی دارند جستجو می‌کنند.
drink any kind of water, develop all kinds of diseases, what can you do?
موقع جستجو هر آبی که باشد می‌خورید و مبتلا به انواع بیماری‌ها می‌شوید. چه می‌شود کرد؟
You are seeking after all, you are thirsty. It has to be excused.
هر چه باشد دارید جستجو می‌کنید. تشنه‌اید. باید یک بهانه‌ای باشد.
And that's how they develop lots of problems,
‌و به این ترتیب آنها دچار انواع مشکلات می‌شوند؛
not only in their body but also in their brain.
نه فقط در بدنشان، بلکه در مغزشان.
And now it's a very delicate thing. If you tell somebody
و این مورد بسیار ظریفی است. اگر به کسی بگویید:
that you have been to such and such guru, he doesn't want to hear
شما پیش چنین و چنان استادی رفته‌ای؛ قبول نخواهد کرد.
because for him now the guru has become the last word.
چون برای او آن استاد حرف آخر را می‌زند.
You cannot say anything against his guru.
نمی‌توانی حرفی علیه استادش بزنی.
Now when he starts suffering, then he may accept,
حالا وقتی مشکلاتش شروع شوند، شاید قبول کند؛
but to take it out that guru is also very delicate
ولی خارج کردن آن استاد هم کار ظریفی است
because if you want to take out that guru, then he might be hurt.
چون، اگر بخواهی آن استاد را خارج کنی، ممکن است او آسیب ببنید.
So it's a very delicate operation.
بنابراین عمل جراحی بسیار ظریفی است.
Then the modern society, the less said the better.
بعد این جامعه مدرن؛ که هر چه کمتر گفته شود بهتر است!
The norms of modern society are given to us by people
معیارهای جامعه مدرن را کسانی برای ما تعیین کرده‌اند که بی‌هویت بودند؛
who were characterless like Freud, who had no sense of morality,
مثل فروید، که هیچ بویی از اخلاقیات نبرده بود،
or by drunkards, though they don't have any statues of drunkards.
و یا افراد میخواره؛ با این که هیچ مجسمه‌ای از الکلی‌ها ندارند،
But most of them, if you see the abandonment of our value system comes through drinking.
ولی اگر دقت کنید می‌بینید فساد اخلاقی درسیستم ارزشی ما ناشی از میگساری است.
And the drinking was there but not to this extent, I mean,
و میخوارگی قبلا هم بوده ولی نه در این حد.
everybody was not a drunkard, these days everybody can be a drunkard.
یعنی همه دیگر دائم‌الخمر نبودند. ولی این روزها هر کس را که می‌بینی ممکن است دائم‌الخمر باشد
And there's no shame about it. With that drinking
و هیچ شرمی هم از آن ندارند.
our value system started dropping down and people have accepted now,
با چنان میگساری، سیستم ارزشی ما رو به سقوط گذاشت و مردم حالا پذیرفته‌اند
the normal thing is abandonment. This is another way.
که بی‌بندوباری امری طبیعی است. این هم جنبه‌ای دیگر.
Formerly the parents used to support the person if he would take to God,
پیش از این، پدر و مادرها از افرادی که سمت خدا می‌رفتند،
if he would take to righteous life or to something higher.
دنبال زندگی سالم یا بالاتر از آن بودند حمایت می‌کردند
And if they saw these qualities in their child they used to be happy,
و اگر این خصوصیات را در فرزندشان می‌دیدند خوشحال بودند.
but these days the other way round, the parents don't like it.
ولی امروزه برعکس است. پدر و مادرها از چنین چیزی خوششان نمی‌آید.
As if the parents have lost everything in themselves,
ظاهرا چون این والدین خیلی خودشیفته هستند،
so they want to hold on to their children, grandchildren and possess them.
می‌خواهند به بچه و نوه خود بچسبند و آنها را در تملک خودشان در بیاورند
And brainless creatures, because their brain has been already washed out,
و موجودات بی‌مغزی هستند؛ چرا که مغزهایشان قبلا شستشو داده شده است.
there's nothing in their brains. To fight the parents also is a big problem.
هیچ چیزی در مغزشان ندارند. جنگیدن با والدینشان هم مشکل بزرگی است.
So this kind of a fear is also there, that: "My mother should not know,
بنابراین نوعی ترس وجود دارد که مادرم نباید بفهمد،
my father should not know," this, that.
پدرم نباید بفهمد، این، آن،
You can say from all sides
می‌شود گفت از هر طرف
the fear is burning, like flames.
ترس دارد مثل شعله‌ای زبانه می‌کشد
And we are now here, in Kali Yuga, we have started Sahaja Yoga.
و ما الان اینجا در کالی یوگا هستیم. ما ساهاجایوگا را شروع کرده‌ایم.
So the way we have to work out our protection has to be mutual.
پس راهی که باید برای حفاظت از خودمان بپیماییم دوطرفه است.
Mother of course is there to protect you all the time,
درست است مادر البته برای حفاظت از شما همیشه هست.
Her powers are there to protect you.
قدرت‌های او برای حفاظت از شماست.
But surprisingly in the modern times,
ولی جالب است که در زمانه جدید،
there's one condition which has to be fulfilled.
یک شرط وجود دارد که باید به آن عمل شود.
Because in those days good were good
چون در آن دوران، خوب خوب بود
and evil were evil, there was no mixing up.
و بد، بد. هیچ آشفتگی وجود نداشت.
So once they asked for Goddess, they accepted Her,
به همین دلیل وقتی ایزدبانو را طلب می‌کردند، او را قبول داشتند،
She came in Her real form and She worked it out.
ایزدبانو به شکل واقعی خودش می‌آمد و کار را تمام می‌کرد.
But in modern times, you must know that all these evil things
ولی باید بدانید در دوران جدید همه این شیاطین دارند
are also lingering in your head, little bit here and there.
در مغز شما پرسه می‌زنند، کمی اینجا و آنجا.
People are extremely superficial,
مردم بسیار سطحی هستند.
they are very much prone to the mass attitude, fashions, things like that.
بسیار مایلند که به رنگ جماعت درآیند و دنبال مد و چیزهایی مثل آن هستند.
Sort of, their personality is not that developed as that
به نوعی شخصیت آنها شکل نگرفته،
of those bhaktas who knew they were right, who knew they were righteous,
نه مثل آن سرسپردگانی که می‌دانستند حق با آنهاست
who knew whatever they were doing was correct
و می‌دانستند که درست می‌گویند، می‌دانستند که هر کاری که می‌کنند درست است
and were standing on their legs firm.
و آنها روی پاهای خودشان ایستاده بودند. محکم.
So the modern Sahaja Yogi is very different from the Sahaja Yogi of olden times.
بنابراین ساهاجایوگی‌های جدید با ساهاجایوگی‌های زمان‌های قدیم خیلی فرق دارند،
Because in the olden times it was not easy to get Realization.
چون در زمان‌های قدیم خودآگاهی گرفتن کار آسانی نبود.
One in a billion, or in a trillion.
یکی در میلیارد یا در تریلیارد می‌گرفت.
And they had to work very hard, so as they worked hard, very hard,
و آنها باید خیلی سخت کار می‌کردند. و چون سخت کار می‌کردند، خیی سخت،
they got cleansed and built up themselves, you see, and toiled.
پاک می‌شدند و خودشان را قوی می‌کردند و زحمت می‌کشیدند.
Like any art piece which takes time, is done with care,
مثل هر اثر هنری که زمان می برد، با صرف وقت و دقت به وجود می‌آید،
is definitely thousand times better than these modern artists
هزاران بار بهتر از این هنرمندهای جدید است
just putting two, three lines like this.
که فقط دو سه خط می‌کشند.
So the today's human being is like a modern artist, you see.
برای همین انسان امروزی مثل یک هنرمند جدید است.
You put one line and you say: "You must see this into that person,
یک خط می‌کشید و می‌گویید: باید این را در آن شخص ببینید،
you must have an identity." I mean, what identity people can have?
باید یک هویتی داشت. چه هویتی می‌شود داشت؟
With one line, you say, find out the identity.
با یک خط بگویید: هویتش را تشخیص بده.
So the Sahaja Yogis which are today here, have to realize
ساهاجایوگی‌هایی که امروز اینجا هستند باید متوجه شوند
that all these things are surrounding us, and these evil forces are also there.
که دور و بر ما را همه این چیزها گرفته و این نیروهای شیطانی هم اینجا هستند؛
There are some within us, some are without.
بعضی‌هایشان درون و بعضی بیرون ما هستند.
So it's a - looks to be very difficult task, but it's not.
برای همین به نظر می‌آید که کار بسیار سختی است؛ ولی نیست.
Because one condition if you can understand,
چون اگر متوجه شوید یک شرط دارد؛
is that you have to recognize Me.
که شما باید مرا بشناسید.
I know I am Mahamaya, I'm really very clever at it.
می‌دانم، من ماهامایا هستم. واقعا در این کار زرنگ هستم.
But I am truthful, I do not have crocodile tears, I cannot have.
ولی راستش را می‌گویم. اشک تمساح ندارم. نمی‌توانم داشته باشم.
I am truthful, but still I am Mahamaya.
راستش را می‌گویم. با این حال ماهامایا هستم.
So to recognize Me what should we do?
پس برای شناختن من چه باید کرد؟
If we recognize then you are protected.
اگر ما بشناسیم حفاظت خواهید شد.
And the cleansing is the simplest thing in Sahaja Yoga is to be collective.
و پاک کردن، آسان‌ترین کار ساهاجایوگا است که باید جمعی باشیم.
If you are not collective then know that something wrong with you.
اگر جمعی نیستید، بدانید که مشکلی دارید،
If you are collective then as if you are taking your bath in the river Ganges.
اگر جمعی باشید، انگار دارید در رود گنگ حمام می‌کنید.
You don't have to go to Himalayas, you don't have to do individual sadhana much,
لازم نیست بروید هیمالیا، لازم نیست خیلی ساداناهای فردی انجام دهید.
you don't have to... just be collective. If you are collective,
فقط جمعی باشید! اگر جمعی هستید،
if you are enjoying the collective, then you should know that you are clean.
اگر از جمع لذت می‌برید، باید بدانید که پاک هستید،
No blemishes there, you are absolutely all right.
هیچ عیبی وجود ندارد. شما کاملا خوب هستید.
Now the second part of is - this Mahamaya business.
حالا دومین بخش وظیفه ماهامایا هست؛
I had to be very close to you, I had to be extremely close,
من باید خیلی به شما نزدیک باشم. باید به شدت به شما نزدیک می‌شدم.
talk to you, to have a rapport, to tell you everything about Yoga
با شما صحبت کنم، گفتگو کنم، همه چیز را در مورد یوگا بگویم
to make you absolutely aware of yourself. This had to be done,
خودتان را به خودتان بشناسانم، این کار باید انجام می‌شد
and with all these complications within your mind,
و با همه این پیچیدگی‌های موجود در درون مغز،
within your heart, within your body, I had to work it out.
قلب و جسمتان باید از عهده آن برمی‌آمدم.
To come close in the real form would have been very dangerous,
نزدیک شدن به شکل واقعی، خیلی خطر ناک بود؛
so One had to be a Mahamaya. But despite that,
برای همین باید ماهامایا بود. ولی با این وجود،
if you could recognize Me, to understand Me,
اگر بتوانید مرا بشناسید و درک کنید
that I am Divine personality, it's an Incarnation -
که من شخصی خدایی هستم، این یک اینکارنیشن است.
that's all the Deities want. Then they'll look after you in every way.
درست همان چیزی است که دیتی‌ها می‌خواهند. آنها به هر شکلی از شما مراقبت می‌کنند.
They'll give you all the powers, they'll give you all the satisfaction,
به شما تمام قدرت‌ها را می‌دهند. به شما رضایت کامل
all the protection that you want. This is the condition
و هر حمایتی که لازم دارید می‌دهند. این شرطی است
which for a rational mind is very difficult to understand,
که درک آن برای یک مغز منطقی بسیار سخت است؛
that how can Adi Shakti be in one body?
که چطور می‌شود آدی شاکتی به یک جسم درآید؟
How can the Infinite can become finite?
چطور یک بی‌نهایت می‌تواند محدود شود؟
But human beings cannot do that.
ولی انسان‌ها نمی‌توانند این کار را بکنند.
Only human beings. God can do it. He is God after all.
فقط انسان‌ها. خداوند می‌تواند، هر چه باشد او خداست.
And if so, you have so many miracles, you have so many photographs,
و اگر چنین است؛ شما معجزات زیادی را می‌بینید، شما عکس‌های زیادی دارید؛
so many things to see, but this is what one has to recognize.
خیلی چیزها هست که ببینید، ولی لازمه‌اش آن است که شخص بشناسد.
Now I see people, when I talk to them
حالا کسانی را می‌بینم که وقتی با آنها صحبت ‌می‌کنم،
they start talking to Me a little frivolously,
کمی با سبک‌سری با من حرف می‌زنند،
not with that depth, not with that feeling that I am Mahamaya.
نه با آن عمق و با آن حسی که من ماهامایا هستم.
Then some of them even answer Me. Some of them, if I tell them something,
بعد یک عده از آنها حتی جواب هم می‌دهند. بعضی از آنها اگر چیزی بگویم
they are ready to give an answer, explanation.
آماده‌اند که جوابی بدهند، توجیه کنند.
Of course this freedom I have given you deliberately,
البته این آزادی‌ای است که خودم عمدا به شما داده‌ام؛
but must understand that you have to talk to Me
ولی باید فهمید که با من طوری صحبت کنید
in a way that is, you would talk to Adi Shakti.
که با آدی شاکتی صحبت می‌کردید.
Very important.
خیلی مهم است.
Then how you behave is very important. You should not be artificial,
بعد طرز رفتار شما هم خیلی مهم است. نباید مصنوعی باشد.
you should not be superficial, but best is to put your hand on your heart,
نباید ظاهری باشد. بهترین کار این است که دستتان را روی قلبتان بگذارید،
both the hands, and just try to feel it.
هر دو دستتان را و سعی کنید آن را احساس کنید.
Your Mother is Adi Shakti.
مادر شما آدی شاکتی است،
She has created all this Universe, She has created all this world,
او تمام این عالم را خلق کرده است، او تمام این دنیا را خلق کرده،
She is for your protection. Even Shri Krishna could not protect
و اینجا است که شما را حفاظت کند. حتی شری کریشنا هم نمی‌توانست پانداواها را حفاظت کند.
Pandavas - they had to go in the forest, they had to suffer.
آنها باید به جنگل می‌رفتند، باید زجر می‌کشیدند،
But not Sahaja Yogis.
ولی نه ساهاجایوگی‌ها.
As soon as I come to know about your problems, My attention can work out.
به محض این که از مشکلات شما باخبر شوم، توجه من می‌تواند کار کند.
Shri Rama Himself had to go to jungles.
شری راما خودش مجبور شد به جنگل برود.
All this is given to you, this protection, because you are seekers of truth,
همه این‌هایی که به شما داده شده، این حفاظت، به این خاطر است که شما جستجوگر حقیقت هستید
and the truth is that I am the Adi Shakti incarnated.
و حقیقت این است که من آدی شکتی هستم که بر زمین آمده‌ام.
Once this truth becomes one with yourself
وقتی که این حقیقت با شما یکی شود،
there is nothing to fear, because all the Deities know this fact,
چیزی برای ترسیدن باقی نمی‌ماند؛ چون همه دیتی‌ها این حقیقت را می‌دانند.
they know about this Incarnation very well. They are all prepared for it,
آنها این اینکارنیشن را به خوبی می‌شناسند، آنها همه به خاطر این خود را آماده کرده‌اند
and they'll do anything to substantiate your belief.
و هرکاری را برای محقق کردن عقیده شما انجام می‌دهند.
In every way they are trying to give you My photographs, in the sky, this, that,
به هر شکلی سعی می‌کنند که به شما عکس‌های مرا بدهند، در آسمان، این، آن،
I mean all sorts of things. God knows what they are going to do today.
همه چیز. خدا می‌داند امروز می‌خواهند چه کار کنند.
They are so anxious.
آنها خیلی مشتاق هستند.
They are behind the stage, before the stage, all sides of the stage,
آنها پشت سن، جلوی سن، در همه جای سن،
listening to Me, feeling happy that I am telling you the truth.
دارند حرف‌های مرا گوش می‌کنند و خوشحالند که دارم به شما حقیقت را می‌گویم.
But the way they recognize and the way they act, they never disobey.
ولی آن طور که آنها می‌شناسند و طوری که عمل می‌کنند؛ آنها هیچ وقت سرپیچی نمی‌کنند.
If you behave in the same manner
اگر شما به همان شکل عمل کنید،
you are completely protected from all these problems I have told you about.
از تمام مشکلاتی که درباره‌اش با شما صحبت کردم، کاملا مصون خواهید ماند.
Now I won't say you shouldn't hate anyone, you shouldn't do.., nothing of the kind.
حالا نمی‌گویم نباید از کسی متنفر باشید، نباید این کار را بکنید، اصلا و ابدا.
I wouldn't say you should not steal something.
نمی‌گویم نباید چیزی را بدزدید،
I wouldn't say that you make money, don't make money out of Sahaja Yoga, nothing.
نمی‌گویم که نباید از ساهاجایوگا پول درآورید. اصلا؛
I don't even say don't drink, don't smoke, I never said so.
حتی نمی‌گویم نباید مشروب بخورید، نباید سیگار بکشید، هیچ‌وقت چنین حرفی نمی‌زنم.
But automatically once you know whom you are facing,
ولی خود‌به‌خود وقتی بفهمید در مقابل چه کسی قرار دارید،
in whose protection you are, automatically you will do that.
در حمایت چه کسی قرار دارید، خود‌به‌خود این کار را ترک خواهید کرد.
Automatically. You will have no fear.
خود‌به‌خود. هیچ ترسی نخواهید داشت.
Once you have recognized you will have no fear from anyone.
وقتی شناخت پیدا کنید، از هیچ کس هراسی نخواهید داشت.
And the more you show that recognition, the more you realize it,
و هر چه بیشتر این شناخت را نشان دهید هر چه بیشتر آن را متوجه شوید،
you get higher and higher. Not only spiritually,
شما بالا و بالاتر خواهید رفت. نه تنها از نظر معنوی،
but every way - mentally, socially, economically, politically.
بلکه از هر نظر؛ ذهنی، اجتماعی، اقتصادی، سیاسی.
It's very remarkable
این خیلی فوق‌العاده است
that not only that you recognize Me as a Mother who loves you very much,
که نه تنها مرا به عنوان مادری خواهید شناخت که شما را خیلی دوست دارد،
but a Mother who is powerful to protect you, She’s very powerful.
بلکه به عنوان مادری که قدرت دارد شما را حفاظت کند، خیلی قدرت دارد.
If you realize that, and if you feel that within your heart,
اگر این را متوجه شوید و در قلبتان احساس کنید.
supposing I correct you sometime, instead of feeling sad you should see it
برفرض گاهی شما را اصلاح می‌کنم. به جای آن‌ که احساس ناراحتی کنید، باید ببینید
that "How fortunate I am that Adi Shakti Herself is correcting me.
که چه خوشبختم من که آدی شاکتی شخصا دارد مرا اصلاح می‌کند.
She is taking interest in me.
او دارد به من علاقه نشان می‌دهد.
How fortunate I am to be born at this time,
چقدر خوشبختم من که در این زمان به‌ دنیا آمده‌ام
to be with Her in Her great work, what have I done?"
که با او در کار عظیمش هستم. مگر من چه کرده‌ام؟
This recognition itself will fulfil all the incarnations of Navaratri.
این شناخت، خودش تمام اینکارنیشن‌های نورتری را راضی می‌کند.
So today we are worshipping the Durga, Kali,
امروز روزی است که داریم دورگا، کالی،
all these great Goddesses, these Powers, even Radha.
تمام این ایزدبانوان بزرگ را ستایش می‌کنید، این قدرت‌ها را. حتی رادْها را،
It was Radha who killed Kamsa not Shri Krishna.
این رادْها بود که کامسا را کشت، نه شری کریشنا.
He had to ask Radha to come and kill him. It's the Power that kills.
او باید از رادْها می‌خواست که بیاید و کامسا را بکشد. این قدرت است که می‌کشد.
So if you realize
بنابر این اگر متوجه شوید
that your Mother is the Adi Shakti.
که مادرتان آدی شاکتی است.
I know of so many people.
من خیلی‌ها را می‌شناسم.
There's one gentleman who is working in London airport.
آقایی بود که در فرودگاه لندن کار می‌کرد.
Somebody tried to trouble him. He said: "You see, be careful of?ah...
کسی خواست که او را به دردسر بیندازد. گفت ببین: مراقب باش،
my Mother is very powerful, you don't know."
مادر من خیلی قدرتمند است، شما نمی‌دانی؛
Next day that man lost his job, lost his business, lost this, lost this,
فردایش آن مرد شغلش را از دست داد، کاسبی‌اش را از دست داد، این را از دست داد، آن را از دست داد.
and he came to him and said: "Now which is your Mother, let me see Her?"
و پیش او آمد و گفت: حالا این مادرت کدام است؟ بگذار او را ببینم.
There was a farmer in, near Rahuri,
یک کشاورزی نزدیک راهوری بود
and in the night three men came to steal some sugar cane.
و در شب سه نفر آمدند که مقداری نیشکر بدزدند.
And next day they came and they said: "Which Goddess do you worship?"
و فردا آمدند و گفتند: تو کدام ایزدبانو را می‌پرستی؟
He said: "Why?". "There were three hefty people watching your - guarding your field,
گفت: چطور مگر؟ سه تا آدم قوی‌هیکل بودند که مراقب مزرعه تو بودند و از آن نگهبانی می‌کردند
and we came just to... and we thought, better take some of this sugar cane,
و تا ما آمدیم که ببینیم بهتر است یک مقدار از این نیشکرها را برداریم،
after all, it looks so nice, and they beat us. Of course we never got hurt."
خوب بالاخره خیلی خوب به نظر می‌رسیدند، آنها ما را زدند. البته صدمه‌ای به ما نرسید.
So just behind this recognition is all the powers.
درست در ورای این شناخت، تمامی قدرت‌ها وجود دارد.
There's so many, so many stories I can tell you,
داستان‌های بسیار بسیار زیادی هست که می‌توانم برای شما تعریف کنم
how things have happened, how it has worked out.
چطور اتفاق افتادند و چطور تمام شد.
But if you are doubting, still halfway, this, that, then things won't be all right.
ولی اگر هنوز شما شک دارید، نصفه نیمه، این، آن؛ آن موقع کارها درست نخواهد شد.
You shouldn't worry about your reputation.
نباید نگران شهرت خودتان باشید.
Just go with full speed into any direction, knowing one thing -
فقط با تمام سرعت به همه جهات حرکت کنید و یک چیز را بدانید
that you are My child, and that I am Adi Shakti.
که شما فرزند من هستید و این که من آدی شاکتی هستم.
Everything that looks horrible will become better.
هر چیزی که وحشتناک به نظر می‌آید بهتر خواهد شد.
We have seen it now in this France case, and all that, what has happened.
این را ما الان برای مورد فرانسه می‌بینیم و همه چیزهایی که اتفاق افتاد.
Don't worry about anything, just know that
نگران هیچ چیزی نباشید، فقط بدانید
I am the Adi Shakti.
که من آدی شاکتی هستم.
That all the powers of Gods and Goddesses and all that are within Me,
که تمامی قدرت‌های ایزدان و ایزدبانوان و تمامی آنها درون من وجود دارد
and they are within Me, and they are all looking after you.
و آنها در من هستند و همه دارند از شما مراقبت می‌کنند.
But if that recognition is not there, they are not going to recognize you either.
ولی اگر آن شناخت نباشد آنها هم شما را نخواهند شناخت.
So for today's Navaratri I have to tell you that just try to keep in mind
برای نورتری امروز باید به شما بگویم که سعی کنید در ذهنتان در نظر داشته باشید
that today you are worshipping the Adi Shakti and not only Durga.
که شما دارید آدی شاکتی را ستایش می‌کنید و نه فقط دورگا را؛
And you are worshipping Durga and all these Goddesses to thank them.
و شما دارید دورگا و تمامی این ایزدبانوان را ستایش می‌کنید تا از آنها تشکر کنید.
Because if they had not saved you that time you would have been so frightened,
چون اگر شما را آن زمان حفظ نکرده بودند، آن قدر می‌ترسیدید
you would have become bad people and you would not have been here.
که آدم‌های بدی می‌شدید و دیگر اینجا نبودید.
That is why we are thankful to them for saving us
برای همین است که ما متشکریم از آنها که ما را نجات دادند
and giving us this protection at that time when we were very helpless.
و به ما در آن زمان این حفاظت را بخشیدند، وقتی که ما بسیار درمانده بودیم.
May God bless you all.
رحمت خداوند شامل حال شما باشد.